Sr. Marketing Manager

Vijesh J Rao

G-204, Gopalan Habitat Splendor

Kundalahalli, Bangalore – 560 037

Ph: +91 98901 93650 E-mail: <u>rao.vijesh@gmail.com</u>

Continue to grow my career in Marketing & Business Development, with an organization of high repute

PROFESSIONAL SYNOPSIS

- → 7+ years of work experience in the field of Marketing, Pre-Sales, and Project Management
- → Currently employed as Marketing Manager in MSC Software Corporation, Bangalore, a leading provider of enterprise simulation solution products and services. Responsible for country wide marketing.
- ▼ Instrumental in setting up Marketing Dept. and related processes for MSC Software in India
- Worked with leading MNCs like Sandvik Asia, Geometric Global and Atlas Copco
- Master's graduate in Mechanical Engineering with specialization in CAE. Bachelor's degree in Industrial
 & Production Engineering. Both the degrees awarded from Manipal Institute of Technology, Manipal
- → An effective communicator with strong Quantitative and Qualitative Analysis skills

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

- SFDC - Market Research - Business Development

- Marketing Communication - Project Management

- Channel Marketing - Brand Management - Event Management

CAREER HIGHLIGHTS

Marketing Manager at MSC Software Corporation Pvt Ltd., Bangalore

(Aug 2009 till date)

(<u>www.mscsoftware.com</u>)

- Profile Responsible for country wide Marketing
 - Prepare and execute yearly marketing plan as per the corporate guidelines and budget.
 - > Run product/industry marketing campaigns Direct & Web.
 - > Monitor SFDC and pipeline growth.
 - Research new and emerging markets in India for potential market expansion and business opportunities.
 - Execute field marketing activities to complement sales strategy and corporate objectives.
 - > Manage and support channel marketing initiatives.
 - Marketing communication through press releases, customer interviews and reference stories.
 - > Build new prospect database and run structured lead nurturing programs.

Sr. Marketing Manager

Project Engineer at Atlas Copco India Ltd., Pune

(Feb 2008 to Aug 2009)

(www.atlascopco.com)

→ Profile – Estimate, Plan and Manage project execution for parent company at Belgium. Research new competencies in compliance with business needs.

Sr. Application Engineer at Geometric Global Ltd., Pune

(Nov 2005 to Feb 2008)

(www.geometricglobal.com)

Profile - Customer Support activities involving leading aerospace, automotive and general engineering companies. Responsible for two software product lines. Also involved in training and mentoring new recruits.

Trainee & Design Engineer at Sandvik Asia Ltd., Pune

(Aug 2004 to Nov 2005)

(www.sandvik.com)

 Profile - Planning and Execution of design and simulation projects for various international clients in Heavy Engineering Industry

ACHIEVEMENTS/AWARDS

- → 'Most Valuable Player of the Quarter' for Q3 2011
- → Member of Sales Force Action Committee (SFAC) representing APAC region since Jan 2011
- → First Runner-up for the 'Personality of Induction Program' at Atlas Copco India Ltd. held in September 2008
- → Awarded as the 'Star Performer of the Month' at Atlas Copco India Ltd. in July 2008
- → 'Team Achievement Award' for the year 2006-07 from Geometric Global Ltd
- Nominated for 'Employee of the Quarter' at 1st QBR held by a Client of Geometric Global in 2006

PROFESSIONAL TRAININGS

- SPIN Selling Training Duration 2 days
- Business Management Training Duration 2 days
- → Business Communication & Etiquettes Training Duration 2 days
- → SFDC Training Duration 1 day

EDUCATIONAL CREDENTIALS

2003-2005	M.Tech in Mechanical Engineering from Manipal Institute of Technology, Manipal
2002-2003	Preparation for GRE & TOEFL
1998-2002	B.E in Industrial & Production Engineering from Manipal Institute of Technology, Manipal

Sr. Marketing Manager

PERSONAL DETAILS

→ Date of Birth : 2nd May 1981

Marital Status : MarriedNationality : Indian

→ Passport : H8146445 (Expires on 18.01.2020)

REFERENCES

→ Shib Bhowmik,

Vice President West Asia

Sandvik Mining and Construction

Sandvik Asia

Pune, INDIA

E-mail: shib.bhowmik@sandvik.com

Phone: +91 99231 29127

→ Mohan Barbela

Principal Technical Representative

MSC Field Technical Support (Aero)

MSC Software Corp. TX, USA

E-mail: mohan.barbela@mscsoftware.com Phone: +1 (817) 240-8750 / +91 97667 33943